<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Django flavoured</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://stard0g101.github.com/</id><updated>2012-07-02T15:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>EuroPython2012 - PyPY</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/EP-2012-pypy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-02T15:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-07-02:EP-2012-pypy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PyPY - The JIT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just in time compiler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cannot cach other jit code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;PyPY - Py3K&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focused on &lt;em&gt;"correctness"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dropped certain interpreter optimizations but will come back to them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of course this is a work in progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most py3k features are implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only unicode identifiers are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; covered yet but as time goes by will be resolved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Whats left then? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first 90% is done &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as always the last 10% is the tough part&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little issuess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have to port the python stdlib due to implementation specific bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to give an idea: Jan 1621 failures in tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;now only 83 failures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most are simple easy to fix grunt work failures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Remove the GIL &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove the interpreter lock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my script is fast already: yes, but does the core speed decrease exponentially.. a lot of a little is a lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python without gil exists already: python 1.4 patch Greg Stein; Jython, IronPython&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demo of script using all 4 cores of Armins laptop being used concurrently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hardware support for the transactional events is coming in 2013 (intel, haswell processor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 catch, you have to use threads! and &lt;em&gt;"threads are a mess"&lt;/em&gt; x2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long demo of examples and then show of code and ilustrating the global counter and transaction conflict that occurs with the GIL setup; not a perfect approach but is still good as it approaches the problem from the right vector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Argh.. watch the cable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is ok computers are cheap ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="pypy"></category><category term="keynote"></category><category term="europython2012"></category><category term="@europython"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>EuroPython2012 - Brain Computer Interface</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/EP-2012-bci.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-02T11:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-07-02:EP-2012-bci.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;BCI - Brain computer interface&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fantastic talk on the potential of BCI; using EEG and ECG the brain sin waves are measured and certain electric potentials are discovered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p300 signal occurs when the brain is focused and surprised by something causes this signal to be evoked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once evoked one can assigne event types to the signal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watching a board of flashing letters one focuses on the letter desired and when it hilights the p300 signal is invoked and thus the user has indicated "w"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fascinating topic, but still very primative and needs much cooperation between many many specialist fields&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not really open source, but one can get involved if they want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bcistandards.org/"&gt;http://bcistandards.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="BCI"></category><category term="keynote"></category><category term="europython2012"></category><category term="@europython"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>EuroPython2012 - Guido Van Rossum Keynote</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/EP-2012-bdfl-keynote.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-02T09:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-07-02:EP-2012-bdfl-keynote.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The hottest week of the year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they are not kidding, its really hot today around 38 degrees celcius. But nevermind were in the hotel and things are hotting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got lots of swag (thanks europython!) shirts mugs and things! all the goodies that come with these conferences!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The #EP people are really friendly and well organized; after picking up my badge after having to spell my surname (sorry Franchesca).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conference is 10% bigger than last year. We have access to the 5* hotels gardens and surrounding areas with shade and ponds and things.. really nice and relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is also woman-friendly and are hosting a #womanslunch; the python community recognizes that more woman need to become involved in the community and we are all urged to talk with woman and try to get them involved and put an end to this man only image that programming has!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EP also offers a free pizza lunch! which we just need to pick tickets up for. But availability is limited so we better book our places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importnat to book the trainings as space in the halls is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intranet is available at #ep to allow participants to deploy and run their demos and software available to all other particippants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightning talks are on offer as well, and if you wish to give one simply register and space shall be yours! As long as your Guido or at least give the correct surname!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water is available everywhere so stay hydrated, but use your Mongodb Cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekend sprints are a go as well as coding competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Guido BDFL KeyNote - all about the trolls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the python software foundation; logos of osf in coffee (lady in japan) gitlatte.com ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completely adlib of his previous talk. Please excuse contradictions if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trolls exist and often crop up at inopportune times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not hard to deal with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horrible language that has GIL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horrible tabs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many silly but also interesting questions that comes from the Trolls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tip for dealign with Trolls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not engage, they go away eventually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Whitespace &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unusual at first, but after a while you will love it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Python sucks ruby rules &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby people tend to say this loudedst and longest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but generally the same argument can be applied to any other dynamic language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all arguments are invalid.. as well as vice versas, "one time at our org we had a very slow python app that was replace with much faster java".. ok fair enough but the same applies jsut as often in the reverse case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remember from 30000 feet all dynamic languages are more or less the same; same similar problems, communities, commercial interests etc.. all dynamic languages are in the same boat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introspection is the key to everything and all languages make the internal workings of the language available (except c...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;static language proponents are activly trying to find ways to bridge between static and dynamic (like google dart)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dart allows optional static binding to dynamic and vice versa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;When will you admit python3 is a mistake&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p3 is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a mistake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more people are still using p2.x and nto p3; but more than he expected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;knew that py3k would take ages to get traction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but it gets better every year. i.e. numpy has excellent support but a year ago it was very shaky in terms of support but now they are all in!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the port of nnupy took effort.... but it was actually not that big a deal!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;constant iterative process, conversion will take some time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some customers are &lt;em&gt;tied&lt;/em&gt; or at least think they are tied to p2.* how do we support them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are a num of strategies to support both 2. and 3k at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 compromise was made in p3k.. string literals prefixed with u u'unicode yay' are &lt;em&gt;STILL&lt;/em&gt; supported in p3k&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this has been done to allow better support for 2.x python in th p3k future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is worh getting into p3k because there &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be a requirement in teh future from your friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because its human nature to want the latest greatest and of course the buzzwords for managers will use p3k&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change sucks, humans hate change and most often the benefits are not obvious to the user; but in a year or two they will think it was silly to make such a fuss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; PyPy - what is going on, why the delay &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guido does not belive pypy is always better; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compat problems, but he is glad they are doing it and taking compat problems so seriously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they are making it better every iteration and its great and faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most systems are dependant on legacy modules and cant simply switch to pypy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still a moving project; but Guido things its doing a great job and would be happy if it took over has preferred python implemntatio but they need tosort out the p3k issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Dynamic typing troll &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;used to be tought that static typing was better than dynamic as static would find bugs at compile time rather than runtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;puritinisim is a sin in itself.. dont be overstrict.. its btter to produce something than let the purity argumetn get in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make it, refine it, make it better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pragmatisim over puritinism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Python is too slow for real work &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;n00b statement; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;compilers are not always the key, dynamic langauges are dynamic for a reason&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the static python compiler is a pipe dream but keep at it maybe someone gets lucky :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube runs entirely on python (except video encoder codex obviously)... not fast enough? are you serious?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The GIL &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problem arises from old legacy timeshare problem which has now changd due to new modern hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are indeed strategies for handeling this problem, but its hard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;python in browser.. cant do it.. but its political and not technical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python in android.. cant do it.. but its political and not technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lambda is NOT broken its great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guido loves functional but io in functional is a problem, at least for him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garbage collection, forget about it its all an intellectual excercise;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional language features.. very selective.. as every new feature adds to the learning curve; and python is meant to be simple and elegant; import this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Questions &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will GAE ever support p3k? : Thats a question for google.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="intro"></category><category term="keynote"></category><category term="europython2012"></category><category term="@europython"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>Countdown to EuroPython2012</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/countdown-euro-python-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-06-26:countdown-euro-python-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Countdown to Europython 2012..&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few more days; I'm placing the final email from the organization here for my own reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Ross Crawford-d&amp;#39;Heureuse,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is our last communication before EuroPython. To make sure you get the best out of your ticket, this is a checklist of things you should know about the conference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an interactive schedule where you can browse, search, favorite talks, create a personalized schedule and so on (make sure to login):
https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/schedule/ep2012/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a (offline) mobile guide through the Guidebook app:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/mobile#guide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4-hours trainings have a booking system in place, through the schedule; booking a seat is optional, but gives precedence in case the room gets full. Login and book your training:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/schedule/ep2012/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching a new helpdesk service at EuroPython: you can book a 30-min slot and get free help from an experienced programmer on a specific Python-related technology or framework. Helpdesk booking is available through the schedule:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/helpdesk
https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/schedule/ep2012/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to join the sprints? Have a look at the sprint list, submit your sprint, or join an existing one:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/sprints/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only talks: browse our participant list by tag, interest, country, and make your personal profile public; get in touch with people you want to meet at the conference before getting there:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/ep2012/whos-coming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still tickets available for Partner Program Tours on Saturday 30th and Sunday 1st (plus others). Take a break from the conference and enjoy Florence, Tuscany, food, wine and museums:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/partner-program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you heard about our tag-cocktails? You might have won free access to one:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/cocktails&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also selling geek-friendly prepaid SIMs with data plans for smartphones (with tethering, no filters on VOIP/Skype, etc.). Have a look:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to join our coding competitions? Google's one requires registration, have a look:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/competitions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submit your question for Guido's Q&amp;amp;A session on Monday:
https://ep2012.europython.eu/blog/2012/06/26/ask-your-bdfl-submit-questions-q-session-guido&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, be sure to subscribe to our blog RSS feed to stay up-to-date with the latest announcements about EP2012!
https://ep2012.europython.eu/blog/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in Florence!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EuroPython Team&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="europython2012"></category><category term="@europython"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>EuroPython2012</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/euro-python-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-06-26:euro-python-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Europython 2012..&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am seriously looking forward to &lt;a href="https://ep2012.europython.eu/p3/ep2012/whos-coming"&gt;EuroPython2012&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference takes place in Florence, Italy. A city that has been on my visit-list for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My collegue "&lt;strong&gt;MartinO&lt;/strong&gt;" and I, depart Dusseldorf on Sunday 1.7.2012 and will be attending for the entire week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is where, I will try to give a running list of the information that is absorbed! Both for my collegues at &lt;a href="http://adcloud.com"&gt;Adcloud&lt;/a&gt; and for whoever stumbles across it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ill try to execute the coverage in the same manner that &lt;strong&gt;Reinout van Rees&lt;/strong&gt; has done previously for &lt;a href="http://reinout.vanrees.org/weblog/2012/06/index.html"&gt;djangocon&lt;/a&gt;.. which I have found to be incredibly informative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference is unfortunately not single-track and Martin and I will try to attend teh most interesting/useful talks of the day. Failing that, then will be outside in the sun eating gelato!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="europython2012"></category><category term="@europython"></category><category term="conference"></category></entry><entry><title>A post from the blue</title><link href="http://stard0g101.github.com/a-post-from-the-blue.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:stard0g101.github.com,2012-04-16:a-post-from-the-blue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Well, that was easy...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to start trying to write a blog. Perhaps this will end up simply being an unremarkable soliloquey; shouted at the walls of the unlistening cave. but it amy also turn into something interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try to write on things of a technical nature; failing that probably just rant somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="first post"></category><category term="hi there"></category><category term="what is this"></category></entry></feed>