<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Django flavoured application development</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/Rails.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Learning the Rails - a start into the ruby on rails world</title><link href="/learning-the-rails-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ross Crawford-d'Heureuse</name></author><id>tag:,2012-04-24:learning-the-rails-part-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So initially I was somewhat taken aback when asked to start working on a Rails project. As a python fan and intermediate user white only a little exposure to the faceted refractive world that is Ruby (on and or off Rails) I was a little aprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a python developer you often are confronted with the latest rant brought to you from the Ruby world; a great deal of which tends to rant about/against python and the various idiomatic differences. Not to mention the strange community in-fighting that every now and again seems to flare up, over this or that topic of the moment (the latest being developers rants against women - Granted this is not a ruby endemic problem but as a whole)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with just a touch of trepidation; we met with the railslove guys and set off on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A week later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well its been an interesting week, introduction to rails generally and commencement of writing tests and learning the ins and outs of MiniTest vs the rest and then the use of FactoryGirl (? seriously guys cmon..)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the whole, ruby is an ok language; I find that it lacks the finess of python from a purely subjective point of view. I also feel that the language itself is too implicit; parenthesis, implicit returns, strange syntax changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all it feels a bit like a young language that has inherited traces from its forebears (sorry to say this) but it does feela  bit like a slightly improved version of PHP.... yes yes I know meta programming and everythign is an object.. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plus side its quite powerful; and while I still find that the rails approach is actually a few generations behind the django approach to web application development it also feels a bit unmodular with controllers views templates spread through the file system like peanut-butter on a large slice of white bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still undecided; Hopefully it gets better, but judging by the rose colored cheeks and glossy eyes some of the ruby guys get when talking about Rails, im sure that it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can say that in a week of 1 hour a day replicating what wevee done in rails with django I am still a great many streaks ahead, which does prove useful as it allows me to illuminate certain problems before they happen ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lets see what this week brings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rails"></category><category term="ruby"></category><category term="vs django"></category><category term="vs python"></category></entry></feed>